开萝尔:门怎么打不开,本?
Carol: Any time this year, Ben.
本:肯定是锁的问题.
Ben: The lock is messed up.
迈克:问题出在你身上.
Mike: You're messed up!
开萝尔:今天是妈妈的生日,气氛不错,迈克你别诚心捣乱.
Carol: It's been a lovely birthday, Mike.Don't ruin it.
迈克:我可不是为自己,
Mike: Mom, I'm not thinking of me.
是可怜爸爸捧着那么多礼物.
I'm thinking of poor old Dad who has to hold all your presents.
杰森:今天你倒是肯为别人着想,难得.
Jason: How thoughtful.
本:瞧瞧.
Ben: There.
麦琪:今天真是太高兴了,
Maggie: Oh, this has been a lot of fun.
十分感谢你们能为我准备这么一个……
Well, I just want to thank all of you for such a ...
杰森:麦琪,让我先把东西放下行不行?谢谢!!
Jason: Maggie?Can I just put these down first?Thank you.
麦琪:噢!当然可以,
Maggie: Oh.Sure, sorry.
不好意思.我只是想感谢大家送了这么价值不菲的礼物.
I just want to thank all of you for your wonderful gifts.
开萝尔:迈克应该除外.
Carol: Except Mike, of course.
迈克:我怎么了?
Mike: What?
开萝尔:下次买香水的时候,千万别在路边小店买.
Carol: Next time you buy perfume, don't buy it at a bowling alley.
麦琪:怎么了,为什么不开灯.
Maggie: Excuse me, why is the light on in the living room?
杰森:我也不太清楚,或许灯泡坏了.
Jason: I don't know, maybe it burned out.
麦琪:啊哈!这跟你有没有关系.
Maggie: Uh-huh.And you had nothing to do with it?
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:开萝尔?
Maggie: Carol?
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
麦琪:迈克?
Maggie: Mike?
迈克:不是我干的.
Mike: Hey, I didn't do it.
麦琪:我们是想开个晚会,给我个惊喜!噢!!
Carol: You guys are throwing me a surprise party!Oh!
杰森:呃,不是你想得那样.
Jason: Uh, no.
麦琪:别演戏了,杰森,你最是诡计多端.
Maggie: Don't ever play poker Jason; you're a terrible bluffer.
迈克:不,妈妈,
Mike: Uh, no, Mom.There's no party.
没什么晚会,我们出去吃饭是因为可以便宜一点.
See, we discussed it and we decided it would be cheaper easier if we just
为了省事,所以没准备晚会.
took you out to dinner.
麦琪:真的!?
Maggie: Right.
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, all these years you've always said how you hate surprise
这些年来你不是总说你讨厌惊喜晚会的吗?
parties.
麦琪:我是说过,可心里想的跟嘴里说的不一样,
Maggie: Yes, but underneath you knew what I really was saying and you
你最明白我心里想些什么的,所以我才这么爱你.
ignored what I was saying and that's why I love you.
杰森:原来如此?
Jason: What are you saying?
麦琪:晚会开始吧.这黑极了,亲爱的,你最好把灯打开,
Maggie: I'm ready for my party.Boy, is it dark in here, honey.
免着我踩着东西或者是人.噢!天呐.
You better turn on a light before I trip over something or somebody.Oh my god.
本:从相关迹象看肯定是有人进来过.
Ben: You know what?Someone's been here.
开萝尔:有贼来过了.
Carol: We've been robbed!
迈克:是.
Mike: Yea.
杰森:都别着急,马上通知警察局.
Jason: Everybody just take it easy.First thing we'll call the police.
麦琪:杰森,你瞧我的小摆设.
Maggie: Jason, look at my knick-knacks.
杰森:什么东西都给偷了,连电话也没放过.
Jason: Well, those thieves didn't miss a thing.They even got the phone.
本:为什么偏要偷我们家,就因为我们姓西维尔?
Ben: Why would someone rob us?We're the Seavers.
杰森:对了,用厨房里的电话.
Jason: Come on.We'll use the one in the kitchen.
迈克:这小偷还算可以没把这部电话给顺手拿走.爸爸你先别碰,
Mike: Oh, good at least they didn't take that phone.Dad!Dad!Don't touch it.
也许会有他们的指纹在上面.
There could be fingerprints anywhere.
开萝尔:我真想狠狠揍他们一顿.
Carol: I'd like to put my fingerprints somewhere.
杰森:都好好听着,你们现在需要的是安静.
Jason: Alright everybody.I just want you all to calm down, ok?
开萝尔:还要我们安静,东西全给偷了.
Carol: Calm down, Dad.We've been invaded here!
本:是啊,他们可能偷了我的东西.
Ben: Yea, they could've taken my stuff!
迈克:还有我的.
Mike: Or mine!
开萝尔:啊噢!我先去看看!
Carol: Uh, excuse me!
麦琪:你们都来瞧瞧,这小偷居然还喝了我冲好的咖啡.
Maggie: Would you look at this?The thieves actually had a cup of coffee.
杰森:你好,嗯!我家被偷了,我叫……
Jason: Hello, yes, I want to report a burglary.Yea, my name is...
麦琪:杰森
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:我知道自己的名字.
Jason: I know that.
麦琪:这还是热的.
Maggie: It's still hot.
麦琪:什么声音?
Maggie: That's a noise!
开萝尔:我不知道,就好像有人穿过树林,拿着一把刀还有枪,还有……
Carol: I don't know, it sounded like someone walking through the bushes with a big
knife and a gun, and they
杰森:瞎想什么呢,开萝尔.
Jason: It's your imagination, Carol.
麦琪:杰森,已经一个小时了,警察怎么还不来?
Maggie: Jason, it has been over an hour.Where are the police?
迈克:现实就是这样,你不需要警察的时候,他们倒不请自来.
Mike: This just figures.There's only cops around when you don't need them.
本:什么时候?
Ben: Like when?
迈克:比如说开车快了点,又比如偷偷溜进快餐店,
Mike: You know, like when you're speeding a little bit or sneaking into
想拿点东西吃,我是随便举个例子罢了.
a drive-in or borrowing a street sign.These are just random examples, Dad.
开萝尔:那些人民警察都死到哪去了?
Carol: Where are those clowns anyway?
本:警察是群小丑?!!
Ben: The police are clowns!
小丑:晚上好,你们是西维尔一家!
Clown: Evenin' Seavers!
杰森:嗯,阁下是?
Jason: Yes, who are you?
小丑:我是生日快乐小丑,我祝麦琪生日快乐,生日快乐麦琪!快乐常在!快乐永存!!快快乐乐每一天!
Clown: [Singing] I'm a happy birthday clown!Happy birthday!Happy!Happy!Happy!
杰森:嘿!嘿!嘿!嘿!你闹够了没?
Jason: Hey!Hey!Hey!Hey!
小丑:你这样实在无礼.
Clown: Well, that was pretty rude.
杰森:是让你九点过来,让你扮演汉弗莱·博格特.
Jason: Well, you were supposed to be here at nine o'clock.
而你却在装小丑开玩笑.
And you were supposed to be Humphrey Bogart.
小丑:哦,开玩笑,
Clown: Oh, wow.You're kidding.I feel terrible.What a mix up.
感觉不对劲!真是倒霉,你是把我当成大傻瓜了.
You must think I'm a total bozo.
麦琪:不管怎样,我都得谢谢你!
Maggie: Thank you anyway.
小丑:我暂时不走,给你们做个大气球,好吗?
Clown: As long as I'm here, want me to make you a balloon rhino?
开萝尔:我最不喜欢大气球.
Carol: Less than anything in the world.
麦琪:杰森,过生日时家里却被透露!杰森,这也太不公平了.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, robbed on my birthday.Jason, it just doesn't seem fair.
杰森:是啊,这是要你好好记住这次生日.
Jason: Yea, I wanted you to remember this birthday forever.
迈克:爸爸,我敢肯定妈妈会永远记住的.
Mike: I think she will, Dad.
本:你们要拿我怎么样.
Ben: What are you people doing to me?
赖特警官:请问你们是是西维尔一家吗?
Officer Wright: Excuse me, are you the Seavers?
杰森:嗯,就是.
Jason: Yes, yes.
赖特警官:我是长岛警察分局的赖特警官,你们家被偷了?
Officer Wright: Officer Wright, Long Island PD.You reported a burglary?
迈克:呃!等等,请问你有证件吗?
Mike: Uh, wait a minute.You got some ID?
赖特警官:你认为我的制服是假的?
Officer Wright: You think these are my jammy's son?
杰森:迈克!
Jason: Mike.
迈克:得了,爸爸.制服在服装店也能借到.
Mike: Come on, Dad.He could've rented that from a costume shop.
杰森:迈克,这人肯定是警察,你就别搀合了,行不行?
Jason: The man is a policeman, Mike, ok?
赖特警官:谢谢.
Officer Wright: Thank you.
杰森:你带证件了吗?算了,开个玩笑!我们相信你.
Jason: Do you have some ID?No, it's ok, no, we trust you.
赖特警官:是不是进屋,请你把情况讲一下.
Officer Wright: So how about we go inside so I can take down your report.
杰森:不知窃贼现在走了没.
Jason: Well, we're not even sure the burglars have left yet.
赖特警官:西维尔先生,一个小时了,
Officer Wright: Mr.Seaver, it's been an hour.
难道你认为他会泡在你家的浴缸里.
You really think he's hanging around in there taking a bubble bath?
杰森:有道理.各位注意,回去吧.
Jason: Good thinking.Ok everybody, come on, let's go.
麦琪:杰森,我还是有点怕.
Maggie: Jason, I am still scared.
杰森:你瞧这警察壮的像头大公牛,你就放心吧.
Jason: Maggie, look at the size of this guy.I feel safe.
麦琪:拿好.
Maggie: Ok.
本:你要知道,我外公也是警察,所以这一行我什么都懂.
Ben: You know, my grandpa's a cop, so I know all about it.
赖特警官:我会好好为你们办事的,你放心好了.
Officer Wright: I'll watch my step.
本:可我外公他不是黑人.
Ben: He's not black, though.
赖特警官:人无完人,明白吗?
Officer Wright: Nobody's perfect.
赖特警官:对不起.
Officer Wright: Excuse me.
迈克:可以.
Mike: Oh, right.
赖特警官:很遗憾.窃贼是从这边进来,
Officer Wright: What a shame.
得手后从前门出去的.
He reached right through here and popped the front door.
迈克:嘿!你千万别碰玻璃,
Mike: Hey, come on!You're touching the glass!
否则会把指纹擦掉的.
How are you supposed to take fingerprints?
赖特警官:这样的入室盗窃案,我们不会派警力去仔细追查.
Officer Wright: We don't have the manpower to take prints on a minor crime.
麦琪:小案?小案?你自个倒睁大眼睛好好看看他们把我家都弄成什么样子了.
Maggie: Minor?Minor?!Look what they did to my house!
赖特警官:嗯,但是没人受伤啊.
Officer Wright: Well, no one was hurt.
麦琪:难不成还要怪我们了.
Maggie: And that's our fault?
迈克:你不取指纹,
Mike: Look if you don't take fingerprints,
那你怎么写详细报告呢?
how are you supposed put out an APB?
赖特警官:不用些报告.
Officer Wright: We don't.
迈克:看来他跟神探亨特根本没得比.
Mike: Well, not exactly Miami Vice now are we?
赖特警官:嘿!阁下也不是什么福尔摩斯.
Officer Wright: You're not exactly the Cosby Show, either.
开萝尔:嗯,对不起,我到浴室里去一下,
Carol: Uh, excuse me, but would it ruin any evidence if I go to the bathroom?
会影响现场吗?要是不能进,那就有大问题了.
Cause if not, we're gonna have a major problem.
赖特警官:去吧,没有影响.
Officer Wright: No, that should be ok.
开萝尔:谢谢.
Carol: Thanks.
杰森:警官,指纹你不打算取,那你能干什么呢?
Jason: Well, officer, if you don't take prints, what do you do?
赖特警官:我先搜集比较明显的证据,
Officer Wright: Well, first I look for any hard evidence; you know,
作案工具和窃贼脚印什么的.
burglar tools, footprints...
本:就应当这么着.
Ben: Point of entry.
赖特警官:对.然后把所有失窃的物件作个报表,
Officer Wright: Right.Then we fill out a report listing all your stolen items.
找保险公司就凭这个,
You'll need that for your insurance company.
然后还可以去找到另外一家.你外公也是这样做的?
Then I go to my next burglary call.Is that how your grandpa would handle it?
本:不,他单枪匹马跟坏蛋斗,
Ben: No.He'd single-handedly capture the bad guys, take their guns,
直到把他们抓住,然后市长就奖励他,还请他到家里去吃饭.
and be invited to the mayor's house for lunch and a hoist few.
赖特警官:哇噢!
Officer Wright: Wow.
麦琪:我真是一点也不明白,这怎么算是件小案,
Maggie: Well, say what you want.I don't understand how this is a minor crime.
家里搞成这样,
Our home has been violated.Personal things have been taken.
东西被偷掉这么多东西.我的生日怎么就给弄成这样.
And it's my birthday!
赖特警官:嘿!生日快乐.
Officer Wright: Hey!Happy birthday!
杰森:我们要是暂时不找保险公司索赔,也许你们会抓住罪犯.
Jason: Should we wait before we file the insurance claim?
不会?
Give you guys a chance to find our stuff?Is that a no?
麦琪:杰森,你看这个.
Maggie: Jason, look at this!
杰森:等一下亲爱的.
Jason: Just a second, honey.
麦琪:这是要紧的事.
Maggie: This is important.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:我的独门秘方鸡汤也被他们给喝掉了.
Maggie: My secret recipe chicken soup.It's gone, too.
杰森:也许是哪个孩子把它……
Jason: Well, yea, maybe just one of the kids
麦琪:不不不,都问过了,你不觉得怪吗?
Maggie: No, no, no.I asked them.Can you believe this?
杰森:丢了那么多东西,
Jason: Honey, we're missing a lot of things.
难道就属你的鸡汤重要?
What's so important about your chicken soup?
麦琪:我不是给贼准备的,是给自己做的.
Maggie: I didn't make it for them!I made it for us!
赖特警官:你们都登记上了.
Officer Wright: Well, that just about covers it.
麦琪:你再加上一锅鸡汤.
Maggie: Add chicken soup to that list.
赖特警官:什么?
Officer Wright and Ben: What?
麦琪:鸡汤也许太小了.
Maggie: Or is that too minor?
本:应该记上.
Ben: I'd do it.
赖特警官:好,一锅鸡汤.
Officer Wright: Chicken soup.
麦琪:锅里还有面.
Maggie: With noodles.
赖特警官:好的,要是再发现少什么,请通知我.
Officer Wright: Got it.If there are any additional missing items, there's my card.
本:炸面圈和咖啡.
Ben: Wanna get a seek run a cup of coffee?
赖特警官:今晚不行,没空.
Officer Wright: Mm, not tonight.Too busy.
本:行了,你现在不能去,
Ben: Oh, come on.You don't have to go yet!Stay!Eat!
你要留下来吃饭,妈妈快给他烙饼.
Mom, make him a cake!
赖特警官:不行,小朋友.
Officer Wright: Can't stay little buddy.
本:你要是一走,坏蛋来了谁保护我们?
Ben: But who's going to protect us when the bad guys get back?
赖特警官:嘿!嘿!嘿!甭担心,今晚他们不会再来了.
Officer Wright: Hey, hey, hey.Don't worry.They won't come back tonight.
本:今晚?
Ben: Tonight?
麦琪:连烛台也偷了.可恶!
Maggie: And the silver candlesticks are gone, too.That's about it.
杰森:你还忘了一样.
Jason: Aren't you forgetting something?
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:你妈给我织的那件袖子足有5英尺长的毛衣.
Jason: Well, that sweater your mother knitted for me.
With the sleeve that's five feet long.
麦琪:你手里拿着的不就是那件毛衣吗?
Maggie: It's right in your hand.
杰森:你知道,我也知道,可你妈妈不知道.
Jason: Well, you know that and I know that, but your mother doesn't know it!
麦琪:我妈为织这件毛衣可花了不少心血.
Maggie: My mother worked very hard on that sweater.
杰森:所以我说这才是重大损失.麦琪,
Jason: That's why it's going to be such a tragic loss!Maggie?
怎么了亲爱的.
Honey, what is it?Hey.
麦琪:杰森,他们闯进来偷我们东西,
Maggie: Oh, Jason.They came into my house, they touched our things,
什么都给他们摸过了,就连我的内衣他们也摸过了.
they went through everything.They know what size my underwear is!
杰森:不要紧亲爱的,人没伤就行了.
Jason: Well, we're ok.Nobody was hurt.
麦琪:可他们要是再来怎么办?
Maggie: But what if they come back when we're here?
杰森:他们再来干嘛?
Jason: Why would they come back?
麦琪:那他们干嘛非要今天来.
Maggie: Why did they come in the first place?
本:嗨.
Ben: Hi.
麦琪:嗨,宝贝.
Maggie: Hi, honey.
本:今晚我能跟你们一起睡吗?
Ben: Can I come sleep with you guys?
杰森:当然.
Jason: Sure.
本:嘿!谁也甭想拿我的东西.
Ben: Hey, nobody's getting my stuff!
开萝尔:呃!嗨.
Carol: Uh, hi.
麦琪:嗨,开萝尔,你有什么事吗?
Maggie: Hi, sweetheart.
开萝尔:嗯,今晚……
Carol: Uh, listen, you know, I was wondering.
杰森:进来吧.
Jason: Come on in!
开萝尔:谢谢.
Carol: Thanks!
迈克:嗨.
Mike: Hey.
本:你也害怕了?
Ben: You scared, too?
迈克:我害怕?我来这里是因为不放心你们,
Mike: Me?Scared?Come on, man.
所以特意来保护你们的.
I just, uh, I thought you guys could use a little protection up here.
本:打肿脸充胖子!
Ben: I don't buy that for a second.
迈克:妈妈.
Mike: Mommy!
杰森:谁还醒着?
Jason: Anybody else awake?
众人:都醒着呢!
Everybody: Yes.
杰森:真要命,你们听着,我觉得我们大家都应该起来,把对这件事情的想法谈出来.
Jason: Well, this is silly.You know what I think?I think everybody should get up and we should go explore our feelings about what's happened
开萝尔:这能有什么用?!.
Carol: I don't believe this.
杰森:都起来,起来,
Jason: No, I mean it.Come on.Everybody up!Let's go!
这是医生的药方!大家都快起来,要知道我可是医生.
Conversation is just what the doctor ordered.I know.I'm the doctor.
迈克:爸爸你倒说说这有什么意思.
Mike: I don't have anything to talk about.
麦琪:听你爸的,
Maggie: Oh, your dad's right.
反正大家都睡不着,
We could use some help falling asleep and listening to your father will
听了他的话也许还能起催眠作用.
put us right out.
杰森:谢谢.
Jason: Thank you.
麦琪:我不是这意思,究竟什么意思我也部知道,
Maggie: I didn't mean that.I don't know what I meant, but I didn't mean that.
好吧,我是这意思.
Ok, I meant it.
杰森:好的,大家开始说话啊.
Jason: Come on, let's go.
迈克:爸爸,要不要叫醒本?
Mike: Hey, Dad.You want me to wake Ben up?
开萝尔:叫醒他,再问他为什么睡不着?
Carol: So he can find out why he's having trouble sleeping?
你的主意还真是厉害啊,迈克.
Oh, good Mike, good.
杰森:我们家从来没有发生过这种情况,所以必须分析一下大家的焦虑状态,
Jason: Well since something like this has never happened to us before
以及大家的心情,
it's important we dig into our anxiety.
必须挖得深一点,透一点.
exam our feeling, we've got to go inward and downward.
麦琪:知道,我去煮咖啡.
Maggie: I know, I'll make coffee.
杰森:喝了能睡得着吗?
Jason: That will help up sleep?
麦琪:没咖啡因的,我懒得跟你争,杰森.
Maggie: Ok, decaf.I'm in no mood to argue, Jason.
杰森:好的,孩子们,说说你们心里有什么不痛快.
Jason: Ok, kids.Come on.Let's talk about what's bothering us.
开萝尔:这个问题我觉得我们完全没有必要来谈.
Carol: I see no reason whatsoever to discuss this a moment longer.
杰森:万事开头难,迈克,请继续.
Jason: That's a good start.Mike?Mike.
迈克:好吧,是啊是啊,
Mike: Oh, right, right.Yea, yea, that's a real good start, Carol.
是良好的开端,开萝尔,我们现在研究你为什么那么怪好吗?
Let's, let's get in touch a little bit with why you're so weird, alright?
杰森:不是说这个……
Jason: This is not...
开萝尔:这次遭窃我看肯定是你哪个混蛋朋友干的好事.
Carol: I bet one of your scum ball friends had something to do with this burglary.
迈克:嘿!绝不许你诬蔑我朋友.
Mike: Hey!Don't talk about my friends like that, alright?
波纳和埃迪想破脑袋也想不出这么好的点子.
Eddie and Boner are too stupid to think of something like this.
开萝尔:瞧你那德行.
Carol: You stinking...
迈克:什么?
Mike: Stinking what?
杰森:嘿!
Jason: Hey!
开萝尔和迈克:怎么了
Carol and Mike: What?!
杰森:这样很好,
Jason: See, this is good.
你们俩现在的怒火,完全来源于刚才发生的盗窃,
See the anger you two are feeling right now is a carry over from the burglary
这倒是可以好好分析分析……
and it's good to...
开萝尔:爸爸.
Carol: Dad.
杰森:等我把话说完.麦琪??
Jason: Let me finish!Maggie?
杰森:你在干什么,亲爱的.
Jason: Honey, what is it?
麦琪:什么怎么了.
Maggie: What is what?
杰森:你不是说来煮咖啡的吗?
Jason: You came in here to make coffee.
麦琪: 你要我煮咖啡吗,杰森.
Maggie: You want me to make coffee?
你们大家不是都在说睡不着吗?
Jason, we're having a hard enough time getting to sleep as it is.
杰森:嗯,请你坐在这边,
Jason: Great, then let's just go in and sit down and talk about what's
给大家说说为什么你心里恼火.
disturbing us.
麦琪:我心里没有恼火,我要把那个贼碰过的东西,
Maggie: Oh, nothing's disturbing me.
一件一件的消毒.
Just because I want to sterilize everything that scum touched.
杰森:我知道,我知道.
Jason: I know, I know.
麦琪:他喝过一杯咖啡,
Maggie: I mean, he had a cup of coffee,
他使用过的咖啡壶你用吗?
you want to drink out of the same coffee pot he did?
杰森:亲爱的,我不喝咖啡.
Jason: Honey, I don't even want coffee.
麦琪:那你为什么要我来煮咖啡呢?本?
Maggie: Well, then, what did you ask me to make it for?Ben!
麦琪:本,睡得好好的干嘛要大喊大叫?
Maggie: Ben, why are you screaming?
本:我突然醒了,发现你们都没了,我还以为你们也被窃贼给偷了.
Ben: When I woke up you guys were gone.I thought somebody stole you.
迈克:果然够聪明!!
Mike: Oh, grow up, Ben.
杰森:别老是针对他,迈克.
Jason: Will you go easy on him, Mike?Ben, we're going to be downstairs.
本,我们在楼下讨论,你要不要也下来说说你的问题.
If you want to join us, we're going to be talking through our feelings.
本:我好得很,没什么好谈的.
Ben: I don't have any feelings.I'm fine.
杰森:你好得很?
Jason: You're fine?
本:我把裤子换掉就下来.
Ben: I will be as soon as I change my shorts.
杰森:好了,迈克,你待会再谈.本,你想说什么呢?
Jason: Ok, Mike, we'll come back to you.Ben, what about you?
麦琪:别嚷嚷,没看他都睡着了吗?
Maggie: He's sleeping.Jason,
杰森,讨论真的非常有帮助,我现在好多了,
this has been very helpful and I feel much better.
要是你同意的话,我得去收拾屋子了.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have some cleaning to do.
迈克:爸爸你说说那些贼,会不会正在贼窝里,
Mike: Dad, do you think the thieves are sitting around the thieves place
讨论他们的想法呢?
exploring their emotions?
杰森:麦琪,你能不能坐下来.
Jason: Maggie, can you just sit down, please?
麦琪:保证不影响你们的讨论,这下行了吗?
Maggie: Well, I can clean while we talk, can't I?
杰森:好吧,请,麦琪请把它关掉.
Jason: Alright, sure.Maggie could you turn that off?
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:你能把它关了吗?
Jason: Could you turn it off?
麦琪:对不起,开吸尘器什么也没听见.
Maggie: I'm sorry.I couldn't hear you over the vacuum cleaner.
杰森:现在已经没事了,安全了,安全了.
Jason: You're ok, Ben.It's all right.You're safe.You're safe.
本:好了.
Ben: Oh, good.
迈克:可是我不大相信.
Mike: I wish I could buy that.
本:你觉得还是不安全?
Ben: Are you saying we're not safe?
迈克:你想想看本,
Mike: Let's put it this way, Ben.
要是再来个身强力壮的盗贼,
If some big dude breaks into the house,
你认为老爸能打得过他吗?
you think Dad is going to wrestle him to the ground?
本:那妈妈呢.
Ben: Or Mom.
杰森:好啦!还有谁认为小偷可能还会光顾?
Jason: Alright, who else thinks there's a possibility someone else will
必须要如实回答,麦琪.
break in?Come on.Be honest.Maggie!
麦琪:必须要如实回答,可实际情况怎么样呢,
Maggie: Well, you wanted honesty.See what happens when you ask for that?
我很真空吸尘器一起不是也挺好的吗.
I was quite happy to stand here with my vacuum cleaner in line.
杰森:很好,就这样.
Jason: No, I'm glad you didn't.This is good.
我说好,
Well, I mean it's good that we're finally able to admit that the reason
是因为我终于发现了使大家睡不着的原因是害怕,人人都害怕.
we can't sleep is that we're afraid.All of us.
本:你也感到害怕.
Ben: You're afraid, too?
杰森:说得没错,本.
Jason: Yes, Ben.
本:爸爸也害怕.
Ben: You're a dad and everything!
迈克:爸爸,你要是再这样说下去,他会发疯的.
Mike: Dad, if you keep going on like this, this kid is going to explode.
杰森:我倒不是想吓唬你们,
Jason: Look, I don't mean to frighten anyone,
不过要是我们不实际点,
but if we don't deal with this honestly,
也许本会拖着箱子去上学.
Ben's going to be dragging that box to college.
本:箱子轻的很.
Ben: It's not heavy.
开萝尔:那我们该怎么办?
Carol: Well, what should we do?
杰森:关键就在这,人人都会经历一些不愉快的事情,
Jason: Well, that's the question.Something terrible has just happened to us.
关键是怎么应对.
What do we do?
迈克:爸爸你提出这个问题,
Mike: Dad, is this one of those questions that you always ask us that
是不是你心里已经有答案了.
you already know the answer to?
杰森:我有些想法,但想先听听你们的.
Jason: Well, I have some thoughts; I'd like to hear yours.
麦琪:我认为该装个报警器,最大的,最响的.
Maggie: I say we get a burglar alarm, the biggest and loudest.
迈克:你还真以为斯维斯特·斯特龙也有报警器?
Mike: Do you honestly think Sylv ester Stallone has a burglar alarm?
麦琪:不,他妻子在自家房子里装有一只.
Maggie: No, his wife got that in the settlement.
迈克:我认为保护自己的唯一方法,
Mike: Look, my point is the only way to protect yourself is with guns.
就是手里一定要有枪.
Lots of them!
本:对.
Ben: Yea!
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No!
开萝尔:你怎么老出这样的主意.
Carol: That's so stupid.
迈克:那你有更好的主意吗?
Mike: You got a better idea.
开萝尔:老实告诉你,我的确有.
Carol: As a matter of fact, I do.
杰森:说来听听.
Jason: Alright, let's hear it.
开萝尔:好吧,事情发生以后,
Carol: Ok.Well, ever since this has happened, I've been asking myself,
我就一直在问我自己,贼为什么要进来.
why did the thieves come here?
本:为什么?
Ben: Why?
迈克:来偷破烂.
Mike: To steal junk.
开萝尔:很正确.
Carol: Exactly!
迈克:这就是大家眼中的天才.
Mike: And they call her the genius?
开萝尔:如果家里没有东西,小偷就没有什么好偷得了,
Carol: You can't steal someone's possessions if they don't have any, right?
对吗?所以答案就是,把家里的东西全扔了.
So the answer is we get rid of all our possessions.
迈克:有谁同意这是世界上最最蠢的主意,请举手.
Mike: Everybody who thinks that's the stupidest idea they've ever heard,
好,该配什么枪,长枪还是手枪?
raise their hands.Alright, what's it going to be rifles or handguns?
麦琪:都不要,我的孩子不许带枪,
Maggie: Neither, I will not have my children armed.It's as rule I have.
这就是我的规矩,很抱歉过去没宣布过.
I'm sorry I didn't mention it before.
杰森:我倒很想琢磨琢磨开萝尔的想法.
Jason: Well, I'd like to explore Carol's idea.
迈克:保证你无功而返.
Mike: This should be a short trip.
杰森:开萝尔,你的意思是连家具也不要.
Jason: Now, wait a minute, Carol.Are you saying we should get rid of our
furniture
开萝尔:没错.
Carol: Yes!
杰森:家电也不要?
Jason: Our appliances?
开萝尔:那当然.
Carol: Sure!
杰森:你的吹风机.
Jason: Your hairdryer?
开萝尔:要从本质上来看问题,吹风机实质上吹的不过是一股比较热一点的风,
Carol: Well, seen in the proper perspective,
根本不算财产.
a hairdryer really is nothing more than concentrated wind which is free
瞧见没,问题不都解决了.
and that's not a possession.See?It all works out!
本:我现在就想要把枪.
Ben: I wish I had a gun now.
麦琪:杰森,我觉得现在应该把我们讨论的问题,
Maggie: Jason, it would be helpful to limit this conversation to reasonable,
集中在一个比较合理的方案上.
rational solutions.
杰森:比如说呢.
Jason: Like what?
麦琪:比如说把房子卖掉,
Maggie: Like putting our house up for sale and moving to a small island
全家搬到缅因州的小岛上去.
off the coast of Maine.
杰森:那为什么不把家搬到法国去?
Jason: Or why not a small island off the coast of France?
麦琪:因为没人会说法语!!.
Maggie: We don't speak French!
杰森:麦琪!
Jason: Maggie!
麦琪:我知道我们不能搬,可是我又觉得这很不安全,
Maggie: Look, I know we can't move,
我只是要求,
but I sure feel like going somewhere that's secure.
要求我的孩子们,
All I want is for my kids to feel as safe as I did when I
跟我小时候那样,有一种安全感.
was a little girl.
杰森:麦琪,别忘了那时候你爸爸可是个警察,谁敢在太岁头上动土!
Jason: Maggie, your father was a policeman.Nobody would rob a cop!
迈克:没错,警察手里有枪,所以没人敢惹.
Mike: Right, because everyone knows that cops have guns!
杰森:枪解决不了问题,
Jason: Guns are not the answer, Mike!
迈克,
Besides, if we had a gun, that could have gotten stolen, too.
即使你有了枪,枪也会被偷走.
And there's a distinct possibility that somebody could get accidentally
还有可能半夜里有个小偷摸进来了把你的枪拿过来对着你就是一枪.
shot while sneaking in here late.
迈克:嗯,倒也是.
Mike: That's a point.
开萝尔:所以,大家同意把东西全扔了.
Carol: So, we all agree.We give everything away.
杰森:说得对.
Jason: Right!
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
麦琪:你们的爸爸他不是这个意思,他是要鼓励大家发言,
Maggie: Now, your father doesn't mean that, he's trying to make a point.
你是要鼓励大家发言,是不是?
You are trying to make a point, aren't you?
杰森:其实,我是觉得开萝尔有道理,
Jason: Well, I think Carol has a good idea.
干嘛不把东西全扔了呢,对,
Why not get rid of all of our possessions?
要是东西扔完了,还有谁来偷呢?
Yea, get rid of everything, that way nobody will rob us.
开萝尔:对.
Carol: Right!
杰森:那就安全了.
Jason: We'll be safe.
开萝尔:完全对.
Carol: Exactly.
杰森:然后坐在这,既快活又安全,赤着脚,光着身子.
Jason: We can sit here, happy and secure, on a bare floor, naked.
本:我不要这样.
Ben: Not me!
杰森:那就留几条地毯当衣服.
Jason: Well, we'll save some rags for clothes.
开萝尔:但千万别用名牌.
Carol: No brand names.
杰森:好的,可要是以后有个人来到了门口,
Jason: Fine!Fine, but then what happens one day somebody comes to the door,
对不起我忘了,门也没了,
I forgot, we gave away the door,
他来到原来是门的那个地方,
somebody comes to where the door used to be and they say well,
他说了,既然你们在这那么快活,
I noticed you're all happy and secure in here,
那么安全,那我就把这个也偷走.
so why don't I just take that away, too?
本:这个人是不是老师?
Ben: Is this person a teacher?
杰森:这没关系.
Jason: It doesn't matter.
开萝尔:爸爸,这种说法毫无意义.
Carol: Dad, the question doesn't make sense.
杰森:为什么?
Jason: Why not?
开萝尔:我认为只要我们有安全感,谁也偷不掉我们的.
Carol: If we're feeling safe and secure, no one can steal that.
杰森:所以只要我们不害怕.
Jason: And isn't that exactly what they...
开萝尔:贼又能拿我们怎么样?
Carol: We're letting the thieves do to us.
迈克:对.
Mike: Yea...
杰森:没错.
Jason: That's right.
本:那我们究竟该怎么做?
Ben: So what the heck are we supposed to do?
杰森:我们不用怕贼,本,
Jason: We don't let them take it, Ben.We carry on.
过正常生活,和平时星期六早晨要做的完全一样.
We do exactly what we would do every Saturday morning.
本:还要老听你骂迈克回家太晚.
Ben: Listen to you yell at Mike for sneaking in late.
杰森:然后呢.
Jason: After that.
麦琪:全家一起出去吃早点.
Maggie: We go out to breakfast.
杰森:对,说吧,你们什么意见.
Jason: Right!Come on, what do you say?
本:那么我的东西有谁看呢.
Ben: But who's going to watch my stuff?
杰森:没人看,本,要么出去吃早点,
Jason: Nobody, Ben.That's it, you see.
要么你就留在这看东西.迈克,你呢?
Either you own your stuff or your stuff owns you.Mike!
迈克:我跟大家一起去吃早点.
Mike: I could eat.
杰森:开萝尔,你去不去?
Jason: Carol?
开萝尔:我早就饿了!闭嘴,迈克.
Carol: I feel like pigs in a blanket.Shut up, Mike.
杰森:麦琪,一起去吧?
Jason: Maggie?
麦琪:我知道你一定有办法解决问题,我一直都相信你的能力,
Maggie: I knew you were making a point.I was sure of it all along.
我从来就没有怀疑过你.
I never doubted you for a second.
杰森:好吧,快点,给你们5分钟换衣服.
Jason: Ok, come on.You've all got five minutes to change.
麦琪:有了杰森·罗兰德·西维尔,谁还希罕斯维斯特·斯特龙.
Maggie: Who needs Sylvester Stallone when we've got Jason Roland Seaver?
迈克:罗兰德??
Mike: Roland?
杰森:快点去换衣服.
Jason: Come on.Get upstairs.
迈克:好.
Mike: Alright.
杰森:快点走啊,本.
Jason: Go ahead, Ben.
本:我把新买的牌带在身上行不行?
杰森:可以,但别让他们听到了.
00:22:29,700
Ben: Would it be alright if I just took my Garbage Pail Kids? Jason: Yea, come on, our secret.